# Alpaslan AKDAG

Computer Engineer | Junior Software Developer 5+ years experience in IT Support | Powercoders Participant Kirchweg 12, 3185 Schmitten FR | 04.09.1985 | Residence permit B Kurdish-TR | Married | two daughters (6,4) alpaslan.akdag@powercoders.org | +41 78 208 77 55

## Github | LinkedIn

Languages: English (B2), German (B1)

Kurdish and Turkish (mother tongue)

IT skills: Upper Intermediate: Oracle, MySQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

IT Support (Maintenance and troubleshooting)

Lower Intermediate: Java, JQuery, PHP

#### **SUMMARY**

I have a Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering and worked more than 1 year as a junior Java developer and more than 5 years as an engineer in IT Support. I am a fast learner and problem solving oriented person who is eager to learn new technologies and likes to work with a team.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

06/2021 - 08/2021

Intern, ECAP, Bern (Switzerland)

- Software Development on ecap-plattfrom.ch with PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS (Bootstrap), MySQL
- IT Support (Installed and maintained company's computer systems. Assisted network device installation and maintenance. Working with Active Directory and domain)

02/2011 - 07/2016

Computer Engineer, DSI-State Agency

(General Directorate State of Hydraulic Works), Sanliurfa (Turkey)

- IT Support (Installation, Maintenance, Troubleshooting)
- Intranet & Internet and Network Devices maintenance

09/2008 - 07/2010

Junior Software Developer, Feza Publications INC., Istanbul (Turkey)

- Reporting with JasperReports on ORACLE DB
- Software development with J2EE, Struts Framework and ORACLE DB on company own web applications

# **EDUCATION**

09/2021 – today Powercoders – Coding Academy for Refugees, Bern (Switzerland)

- Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript; specialization tracks upcoming

- Weekly business & social skills training (team work, communication, etc.)

09/2002 – 07/2008 Bachelor's of Computer Engineer, Selcuk University, Konya (Turkey)

#### **CONTINUOUS EDUCATION**

12/2020 – 03/2021 Java Programming, Duke University - coursera.org

- Programming Foundations with JavaScript, HTML and CSS

Solving Problems with SoftwareArrays, Lists, and Structured Data

- Principles of Software Design

06/2021 – 12/2021 German Course, Delif, Freiburg (Switzerland)

- B2.1 level

**HOBBIES** 

Reading crime novels (my favorite author is Jean Christophe Grange)

playing football, fitness, solving sudoku puzzles.

**REFERENCES** 

Hussam Allaham Industry Lead, Powercoders Deutschschweiz,

hussam.allaham@powercoders.org, +41 77 906 16 27

Arton Pllana Application Developer, ECAP

apllana@ecap.ch, +41 76 738 49 85

Sandra Berneker Social Assistant, Caritas Schweiz,

sberneker@caritas.ch,+41 26 425 82 28